{
    "questions": [{
            "question": "Current Railway Minister of India is",
            "option1": "Mamta Banarjee",
            "option2": "Ram Vilash",
            "option3": "Ashwini Vaishnaw",
            "option4": "Piyush Goyal",
            "answer": "Ashwini Vaishnaw"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which god is also known as ‘Gauri Nandan’?",
            "option1": "Agni",
            "option2": "Indra",
            "option3": "Hanuman",
            "option4": "Ganesha",
            "answer": "Ganesha"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does not grow on tree according to a popular Hindi saying?",
            "option1": "Money",
            "option2": "Flowers",
            "option3": "Leaves",
            "option4": "Fruits",
            "answer": "Money"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city is known as the Pink City of India?",
            "option1": "Banglore",
            "option2": "Maysore",
            "option3": "Jaipur",
            "option4": "Kochi",
            "answer": "Jaipur"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote India's National Anthem?",
            "option1": "Rabindranath Tagore",
            "option2": "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
            "option3": "Chetan Bhagat",
            "option4": "RK Narayan",
            "answer": "Rabindranath Tagore"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many major religions are there in India?",
            "option1": "6",
            "option2": "7",
            "option3": "8",
            "option4": "9",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "When is the National Hindi Diwas celebrated?",
            "option1": "13 September",
            "option2": "14 September",
            "option3": "4 July",
            "option4": "15 August",
            "answer": "14 September"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many states are there in India?",
            "option1": "28",
            "option2": "29",
            "option3": "30",
            "option4": "31",
            "answer": "28"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is India Gate located?",
            "option1": "Agra",
            "option2": "Punjab",
            "option3": "Mumbai",
            "option4": "New Delhi",
            "answer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote Vande Mataram?",
            "option1": "Sarat Chandra Chattopdhyay",
            "option2": "Rabindranath Tagore",
            "option3": "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee",
            "option4": "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar",
            "answer": "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following places is famous for the Great Vishnu Temple?",
            "option1": "Bordubar, Indonesia",
            "option2": "Bamiyan, Afghanistan",
            "option3": "Panja Sahib, Pakistan",
            "option4": "Ankorvat, Cambodia",
            "answer": "Ankorvat, Cambodia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the largest Buddhist Monastery in India located?",
            "option1": "Sarnath, Uttar Pradesh",
            "option2": "Tawang, Arunachal Pradesh",
            "option3": "Dharmashala, Himachal Pradesh",
            "option4": "Gangtok, Sikkim",
            "answer": "Tawang, Arunachal Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Indian monument was originally built as a victory tower to commemorate the defeat of the Khan of Khambhat?",
            "option1": "Qutub Minar",
            "option2": "India Gate",
            "option3": "Charminar",
            "option4": "Vijay Stambha",
            "answer": "Vijay Stambha"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the following was killed during 'Operation Bluestar' of 1984?",
            "option1": "Baba Santa Singh",
            "option2": "Haji Mastan",
            "option3": "Jarnail Singh Bhidrawale",
            "option4": "Homi Jehangir Bhabha",
            "answer": "Jarnail Singh Bhidrawale"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which former Indian President died as a result of a road accident?",
            "option1": "Rajendra Prasad",
            "option2": "Faqruddin Ali Ahmed",
            "option3": "Giani Zail Singh",
            "option4": "R.Venkatraman",
            "answer": "Giani Zail Singh"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the founder of the political party Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK)?",
            "option1": "C.N.Annadurai",
            "option2": "M.Karunanidhi",
            "option3": "M.G.Ramachandran",
            "option4": "Jayalaitha",
            "answer": "C.N.Annadurai"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Indian woman to win a medal in the Olympics?",
            "option1": "P.T.Usha",
            "option2": "Kunjarani Devi",
            "option3": "Bachendri Pal",
            "option4": "Karnam Maleshwari",
            "answer": "Karnam Maleshwari"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Mughal Emperor was deported to Rangoon by the British?",
            "option1": "Shah Jahan",
            "option2": "Bahadur Shah II",
            "option3": "Akbar Shah I",
            "option4": "Bhahadur Shah I",
            "answer": "Bhahadur Shah II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a state of India?",
            "option1": "Vrindachal",
            "option2": "Goa",
            "option3": "Jharkhand",
            "option4": "Chattisgarh",
            "answer": "Vrindachal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the following is said to have witnessed the reigns of eight Delhi Sultans?",
            "option1": "Minhaj-us-Siraj",
            "option2": "Ziauddin Barani",
            "option3": "Amir Khusro",
            "option4": "Shms-i-Siraj Afif",
            "answer": "Amir Khusro"
        },
        {
            "question": "The fine step-well complex of 'Agrasen ki Baoli' is located at",
            "option1": "Gwalior",
            "option2": "Amritsar",
            "option3": "Agra",
            "option4": "New Delhi",
            "answer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "The National Stadium in Delhi was earlier known by the name",
            "option1": "Irwin Stadium",
            "option2": "Mountbatten Stadium",
            "option3": "Wellington Stadium",
            "option4": "Canning Stadium",
            "answer": "Irwin Stadium"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which James Bond movie was shot in the Indian city of Udaipur?",
            "option1": "Diamonds Are Forever",
            "option2": "License to Kill",
            "option3": "Live and Let Die",
            "option4": "Octopussy",
            "answer": "Octopussy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Indian city hosts Indian movie industry?",
            "option1": "Goa",
            "option2": "Mumbai",
            "option3": "Chennai",
            "option4": "Calcutta",
            "answer": "Mumbai"
        }
    ]
}